<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on IT for archivists</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8081/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on IT for archivists</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:8081/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.8 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8081/post/sf178/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8081/post/sf178/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.8 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This minor release updates the PRONOM signatures to v93 and the LOC signatures to 2017-09-28.
As the only changes in this release are to signature files, you can just use sf -update if you&amp;rsquo;ve installed siegfried manually. This minor release is just for the convenience of users who have installed sf with package managers (i.e. debian or homebrew).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.7 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8081/post/sf177/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 16:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8081/post/sf177/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.7 of siegfried is now available. Happy #IDPD17!
Get it here.
This minor release fixes bugs in the roy inspect command and in sf&amp;rsquo;s handling of large container files.
A new sets file is included in this release, &amp;lsquo;pronom-extensions.json&amp;rsquo;, which creates sets for all extensions defined in PRONOM. You can use these new sets when building signatures e.g. roy build -limit @.tiff or when logging formats e.g. sf -log @.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.6 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8081/post/sf176/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 20:12:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8081/post/sf176/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.6 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This is a minor release that incorporates the latest PRONOM update (v92), introduces a &amp;ldquo;continue on error&amp;rdquo; flag (sf -coe) to force sf to keep going when it hits fatal file errors in directory walks, and restricts file scanning to regular files (in previous versions symlinks, devices, sockets etc. were scanned which caused fatal errors for some users).
Thanks to Henk Vanstappen for the bug report that prompted this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8081/post/charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8081/post/charts/</guid>
      <description>In my recent updates to this site I&amp;rsquo;ve added a new &amp;ldquo;Chart your results&amp;rdquo; tool on the siegfried page (in the right hand panel under &amp;ldquo;Try Siegfried&amp;rdquo;). This tool produces single page reports like this: https://www.itforarchivists.com/siegfried/results/ea1zaj.
Before covering this tool in detail let&amp;rsquo;s recap some of the existing ways you can already analyse your results.
Other ways of charting and analysing your results Command-line charting I appreciate that not everyone is a command-line junkie, but the way I inspect results is just to use sf&amp;rsquo;s -log flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.5 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8081/post/sf175/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 20:12:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8081/post/sf175/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.5 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
The headline feature of this release is new functionality for the sf -update command requested by Ross Spencer. You can now use the -update flag to download or update non-PRONOM signatures with a choice of LOC FDD, two flavours of MIMEInfo (Apache Tika&amp;rsquo;s MIMEInfo and freedesktop.org), and archivematica (latest PRONOM + archivematica extensions) signatures. There are two combo options as well: PRONOM/Tika/LOC and the Ross Spencer &amp;ldquo;deluxe&amp;rdquo; (PRONOM/Tika/freedesktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8081/post/reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 21:35:19 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8081/post/reset/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this site. Apologies to those who liked the old look, which used the retro-Windows BOOTSTRA.386 theme. I liked it too. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t have great readability. The new CSS is basic, but it is super lightweight and I can tinker with it. I&amp;rsquo;m using Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s Pure CSS framework.
Under the hood, I&amp;rsquo;ve simplified the site a bit too. It used to be a monolithic golang app, served on appengine, but now most of the static content is generated by Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>