<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>siegfried on IT for archivists</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8080/categories/siegfried/</link>
    <description>Recent content in siegfried on IT for archivists</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/categories/siegfried/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.9.0 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf190/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf190/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.9.0 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This release includes a new Wikidata identifier, implemented by Ross Spencer.
CHANGELOG v1.9.0 (2020-09-22)  a new Wikidata identifier, harvesting information from the Wikidata Query Service. Implemented by Ross Spencer. select which archive types (zip, tar, gzip, warc, or arc) are unpacked using the -zs flag (sf -zs tar,zip). Implemented by Ross Spencer. update LOC signatures to 2020-09-21 update tika-mimetypes signatures to v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.8.0 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf180/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf180/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.8.0 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This release includes changes in the byte matcher to improve performance, especially when scanning MP3s (fmt/134).
CHANGELOG v1.8.0 (2020-01-22)  utc flag returns file modified dates in UTC e.g. sf -utc FILE | DIR. Requested by Dragan Espenschied new cost and repetition flags to control segmentation when building signatures update PRONOM to v96 update LOC signatures to 2019-12-18 update tika-mimetypes signatures to v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.13 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1713/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1713/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.13 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This minor release fixes a in the namematcher that caused filenames containing &amp;ldquo;?&amp;rdquo; to be treated as URLs. It also adds the ability to scan directories using the sf -f command.
Updates to the LOC FDD and tika-mimetypes signature files.
Change Log v1.7.13 (2019-08-18) Added:
 the -f flag now scans directories, as well as files. Requested by Harry Moss  Changed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.12 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1712/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1712/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.12 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This minor release fixes a bug that caused .docx files with .doc extensions to panic and a bug with mime-info signatures.
Updates to the PRONOM (v95), LOC FDD and tika-mimetypes signature files.
Change Log v1.7.12 (2019-06-15) Changed:
 update PRONOM to v95 update LOC signatures to 2019-05-20 update tika-mimetypes signatures to v1.21  Fixed:
 .docx files with .doc extensions panic due to bug in division of hints in container matcher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.11 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1711/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1711/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.11 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This minor release fixes the debian package and allows the container matcher to identify directory names (for SIARD matching). Updates to the LOC FDD and tika-mimetypes signature files.
Change Log v1.7.11 (2019-02-16) Changed:
 update LOC signatures to 2019-01-06 update tika-mimetypes signatures to v1.20  Fixed:
 container matching can now match against directory names. Thanks Ross Spencer for reporting and for the sample SIARD signature file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.10 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1710/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf1710/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.10 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This minor release fixes a regression in the LOC identifier introduced in 1.7.9 and updates to PRONOM v94.
Changelog v1.7.10 (2018-09-19) Added:
 print configuration defaults with sf -version  Changed:
 update PRONOM to v94  Fixed:
 LOC identifier fixed after regression in v1.7.9 remove skeleton-suite files triggering malware warnings by adding to .gitignore; reported by Dave Rice release built with Go version 11, which includes a fix for a CIFS error that caused files to be skipped during file walk; reported by Maarten Savels  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.9 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf179/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf179/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.9 of siegfried is now available. Get it here. According to the develop benchmarks, this release is slightly more accurate than v1.7.8, with only a marginal impact on performance.
The highlights of this release are a new system for saving configurations for the sf tool, changes to the matching algorithm to improve accuracy, and simplifications to the basis field.
Save and load frequently used configurations The new -setconf flag allows you to save frequently used configurations for the sf tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous benchmarking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 20:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>The next siegfried release will be out shortly. I have been busy making changes to address two thorny issues: verbose basis and missing results. I have some fixes in place but, when doing large scale testing against big sets of files, I noticed some performance and quality regressions. You can see these regressions on the new develop benchmarks page. There&amp;rsquo;s also a new benchmarks page to measure siegfried against comparable file format identification tools (at this stage just DROID).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.8 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf178/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf178/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.8 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This minor release updates the PRONOM signatures to v93 and the LOC signatures to 2017-09-28.
As the only changes in this release are to signature files, you can just use sf -update if you&amp;rsquo;ve installed siegfried manually. This minor release is just for the convenience of users who have installed sf with package managers (i.e. debian or homebrew).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.7 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf177/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 16:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf177/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.7 of siegfried is now available. Happy #IDPD17!
Get it here.
This minor release fixes bugs in the roy inspect command and in sf&amp;rsquo;s handling of large container files.
A new sets file is included in this release, &amp;lsquo;pronom-extensions.json&amp;rsquo;, which creates sets for all extensions defined in PRONOM. You can use these new sets when building signatures e.g. roy build -limit @.tiff or when logging formats e.g. sf -log @.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.6 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf176/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 20:12:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf176/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.6 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
This is a minor release that incorporates the latest PRONOM update (v92), introduces a &amp;ldquo;continue on error&amp;rdquo; flag (sf -coe) to force sf to keep going when it hits fatal file errors in directory walks, and restricts file scanning to regular files (in previous versions symlinks, devices, sockets etc. were scanned which caused fatal errors for some users).
Thanks to Henk Vanstappen for the bug report that prompted this release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/charts/</guid>
      <description>In my recent updates to this site I&amp;rsquo;ve added a new &amp;ldquo;Chart your results&amp;rdquo; tool on the siegfried page (in the right hand panel under &amp;ldquo;Try Siegfried&amp;rdquo;). This tool produces single page reports like this: /siegfried/results/ea1zaj.
Before covering this tool in detail let&amp;rsquo;s recap some of the existing ways you can already analyse your results.
Other ways of charting and analysing your results Command-line charting I appreciate that not everyone is a command-line junkie, but the way I inspect results is just to use sf&amp;rsquo;s -log flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.7.5 released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/post/sf175/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 20:12:15 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/post/sf175/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.7.5 of siegfried is now available. Get it here.
The headline feature of this release is new functionality for the sf -update command requested by Ross Spencer. You can now use the -update flag to download or update non-PRONOM signatures with a choice of LOC FDD, two flavours of MIMEInfo (Apache Tika&amp;rsquo;s MIMEInfo and freedesktop.org), and archivematica (latest PRONOM + archivematica extensions) signatures. There are two combo options as well: PRONOM/Tika/LOC and the Ross Spencer &amp;ldquo;deluxe&amp;rdquo; (PRONOM/Tika/freedesktop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
